Welcome to course HDFC Algo Optima
Secure.
So Ayush is here with us to decode this
plan just for you guys and I assure you that
whatever content is made here will be
totally focused for you guys.  Thank you Ayush
for coming.  Thank you so much for having me.
So Ayush, let's start with how this
product is sold in the market.
Every product has a spice.  There is a
tempering.
Correct.
What is the flavour of this product?
So basically HDFCO sells Optima Secure plan
in the market like this, if you
go and check their website then they
write in big letters on the top banner that it is
4x cover amount.  Right?
4x Cover
4x Cover Amount.  Yes, you will
get four times the cover amount you are taking.
HDFC and that is what they say.  What is the meaning of this
?  Four XX cover amount means that
if I take a cover of Rs 10 lakh, I will get Rs 40 lakh directly.
Now let me explain, let's break it down.
Ok?  Firstly Optima Secure is the
flagship product of HDFC Organo
Most.  Ok?  This is a flagship product.
Ok?
Let us divide this four X into three parts.  It is a combination
of three benefits.  Ok?
Ok?   The
first benefit is the secure benefit.
Ok?  What is a secure benefit?  So
secure benefit is basically whatever cover
amount you are buying, whatever cover amount you are going to
take, as soon as your policy is getting
issued on day one, it doubles that
cover amount.
Well,
yes,
if you have taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then
as soon as the policy is issued, it becomes worth Rs 20 lakh.
Direct cover amount.
This is what is secure benefit.  Yes.
This is a very good thing.  Like if I
have money, if I take a cover of Rs 3 crore then it will become Rs 6
crore.
Correct, you are right.  Technically.  But
cover amount up to Rs 3 crore is not available.
In Optima Secure.  Available from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 2
crore.  But you are absolutely right.
If you make 2 crores then you will make it 4 crores.
This is good.  Yes absolutely.
Ok.  So what are the other two?
So the second benefit is plus benefit.
What is Plus Benefit?  Plus benefit is
nothing but a fancy name for cumulative
bonus.  Cumulative bonus is a benefit that is
available across all plans across the industry.
In this plan, the
cumulative bonus is basically named as plus benefit.  In
which whenever
you are renewing your policy, your cover amount is
increased.   Let me
explain the cumulative bonus to you quickly.  Ok?
So basically cumulative bonus is something which is
increasing the cover amount at the time of renewal by the insurance company
by a predetermined specific percentage up
to a maximum limit of a predetermined specific percentage.
In the Plus Benefit of Optima Secure,
they are increasing the cover amount by 50%
at every renewal
up to a maximum of 100%.
So, it is like this that if I have taken the
policy for Rs. 10 lakh sum insured,
okay,
I got the secure benefit, it became 20 lakh,
after one year with that 50%, will my
cover be 30 lakh?
After one year, it will not be 50% of your base cover, it will be
calculated,
okay, the secure benefit will not be calculated,
whatever your base cover is,
you will take 50% of it, that will be added, that
means, on one renewal, it becomes 50% and
keep the maximum at 100%, so on the next renewal, which is going to happen after the
subsequent renewal, your
maximum will be 100%, that has been added
after 2 years,
okay, so, after 2 years, I was
told that the cover will be 4x, but that  One x will be given to me after 2 years, exactly
2x is done on your day one, the
rest of the 100% increase which is happening
through plus benefit will happen after 2 years.
Well, there is something hidden in this which I should know,
the customer should not know, it is
true that these terms and conditions are
generic terms and conditions which are
applicable across the cumulative bonus,
you can take any plan, all those
things are applicable in it also, okay otherwise,
I have already told you about that percentage, it will be
increased from 50%, on two renewals it will be
100% for you,
I understand, we have reached 3x, the rest of that
1x is what I think,
this is the last benefit, basically restore
benefit, okay,
restore benefit means that if you make a
claim in future, then if a claim is made then the
insurance company will restore the full cover amount by 100%.  Now, whether
you have partially used the cover amount or
fully used it, it is for the same illness or for
some other illness.  Nothing matters.
If a claim has been made
and that claim has been paid
then it will be restored.  The full cover amount will be restored to 100%.
So do I have to inform the company to
make this claim or can I make any claim by
informing them?
Obviously, you will have to
inform the insurance company about your claim.   No no,
as if I have
two claims in one year.  One or two, I have a cover of Rs 10 lakh.
We received a
claim of Rs 2 lakh and a claim of Rs 3 lakh.  I
want it to be a store worth Rs 3 lakh because
brother, I will get more money.
Nitesh, the insurance company
tells us a sequence for utilizing the cover amount.
That your base cover amount will be utilized first.
After that your Plus benefit will be utilized.
Then the secure benefit will be utilized.
All this,
when your cover amount is exhausted, only then
they will restore the cover amount.   Ok ok.   Isn't it
?  Even after that, if
you need more cover amount and the claim is made,
then you will get restoration and then
you will get the cover amount.
Restoration will be completed like just the base cover will be.
Only the base cover.
Well, just the base cover.
Yes yes yes.
Good.
Only the base cover.
And This Will Happen Only Once like and this
meaning will always remain on top.
Yes.  So, it is given only once in a year, which is the
basic crystal benefit, which is the main
benefit, it is given only once,
but you can take an add-on
where you can also do it unlimited times, the
insurance company,
well, there is an
add-on, you have to pay a little extra money up
to ₹ 3000, if you
do it then you will get unlimited times
restoration,
understood,
but without add-on, you can do it only once in a year, you
can do it again next year
if needed, so
okay, there are some things which are worth knowing, there are some
hidden things in
this also, terms and conditions,
these are the things which we have talked about,
customers should definitely know all these things,
apart from this, there are similar
generic conditions in this also, which are applicable across whatever
restore benefit you avail
of any plan.  It
is applicable in this also.
Well then.
These are all the things.
understood?  Absolutely.
So basically what is marketed is a
secure benefit.  There is the Plus benefit
and there is the Restore benefit.
When did you
understand the combination of all this?
understood?
Your security has increased 2x.  100% more will be added to
your Plus Benefit after 2 years.  And the
restore benefit becomes
100% only when you claim it.  That has also been added.
For advertising purposes, it has increased
4x.  Then basically, that
last one can happen anytime.   Can happen
anytime.  It depends
on the claim and whether
you have used the remaining cover amount or not.
Ok.  Ok.  Ok.
So This Is The Reality Of Four X Cover.
Nice.   I
mean, I can understand now that he has written four Xs
but what is the reality?
What is the reality?  Yes exactly.
So I am enjoying this thing.  So let's do one thing.
Let me tell you more about
USPs.  There will definitely be more USPs.
Right?  So what are the other USPS of this
product?
So another USP of this plan is
that all limits are not applicable in it.
Accept for only one benefit.   Let
us speak.
What is a sub limit?
Hitesh, the meaning of sub limit is that
whatever cover amount you are buying, there may be a maximum limit defined for
all your benefits on the base basis of that cover amount.
Insurance companies.
For example, if you have taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh,
then as per the policy of Rs 10 lakh, you can claim
only up to Rs 5,000 from the road ambulance cover.
And if you had taken a cover of ₹ lakh,
then the road ambulance deposit would have been Rs
10,000.
Good.   I am
giving you an example to explain.
Ok?
So if all such limits are
based on the cover amount, they keep changing.
As you increase the cover
amount, the sub limit may also
increase.
Got it.
Ok?  Got it.  This plan does
not have all these limits.  Accept for only one benefit.
Which one?
Which is air ambulance benefit?
Could you ebrate a little more on?
Basically, a sub-limit of up to Rs 5 lakh is applicable for air ambulance benefit.
This is a good cover.  Meaning 5 lakhs is a good.
Not necessary.  It depends on where you are from,
meaning you may have to
call a chopper etc.
You have to go from a very remote location to another very far
place.  It is happening.  So it's
not necessary, that means it's very good.
But it depends, it depends.  Got it
on various circumstances and all understood,
this policy doesn't have any kind of submit
accept for this one, this is it
and there are some such terms and conditions in
it, any terms and condition or printed
thing which the customer should know, nothing else
is limited in it,
you can take any treatment, get anything done,
you will not get any submit anywhere in it,
super
let's go
and the good thing which is a good thing
definitely and let's talk about USPs,
some more USPs in this particular
product are
not true, these were the two things.
I have told you these biggest things.
Something means unique selling proposition, this is the
plan.
Ok?
So now let's talk about how would you rate this
product based on the features?
So in product benefits, basically if
I just talk about product benefits,
we have given 4.5 rating in that.
Good out of five.
Ok.
Only in product benefits.
To this to Optima Secure.  Star ratings of course on Which Is One
of the Highest
S.
Got it.  Got it.  Got it.  The product has become a
part.  One parameter is the product
when you are
purchasing a health insurance
policy.  Right?  How is the product?   The
other two components are claims
experience.
After all you are purchasing the plan so that
you get a claim.  Right?  Meaning the product
is very good.  But the claim is not being received.
So what does that mean?
100%
so claim is majority parameter.  We rate that too.
And the third one is
customer service.
Good.
How was his customer service?  Ok?  Of that
particular insurance company.  Right?
Ok?  So we rate this as well,
so let's take it one by one, like if you are, if you are okay, if
you can share
how we are rating the claims, there are like five to seven
parameters that we
consider for rating, the
details of all these parameters, we take it
from the public disclosures of the
insurance respectable insurance companies, some of them we take it
directly from
their website or from their browsers, right,
we take the claims data from
here and there, let's talk about like
a couple of top all the
parameters that we should consider in claims
experience, to check the entire thing, you can
directly go and visit our website, the entire
details will be visible on our website, you will see the complete rating, the
details will be visible,
if we talk about HDFC and GO, then their incurred
claims ratio is around like 80%,
I thought
what happens to such an
incurred claim,
incurred claims ratio, Hitesh, this is what happens
It is a ratio between how much premium an
insurance company is collecting versus
how much claim amount it is paying.
Well, the
ratio of how much premium is coming and how much claim is being paid is basically the incurred
claims ratio,
ideally it should be somewhere between 60 to
80%, if your ICR is between 60 to 80%, that means it is a
healthy
insurance company
got and
HDFC is running at 80% and for
us this is 80%, this is the
ICR, similarly
in public disclosure it is also told
how quickly the insurance company settles the claim, the
percentage of claims they are settling within
30 days, well,
what
percentage of claims does it settle within 30 days of the report, so for
HDFC Arco it is like more than 95%,
okay
more than 95%
for HDFC is a
good number,
this is a good number, 95% is a good number, there are
insurance companies of course which have
more than this,
and you should go to our website and check the
entire comparison, you can easily do it,
okay
but  Yes 95% is also pretty decent
the third parameter the third matrix that we talk about is
the claim complaints that they are getting ki
claim karte samay kitni
complaints aa rahi hai un logon ko that is also very less
for HDFC Ergo it is 07% okay
pretty less right
so considering all these factors Hitesh we
have rated HDFC Ergo s 4.5 out of five in
claims rating
oh
yeah
4.5 out of five
so this is I believe it is a good rating this is a
good rating yes yes this is a good
rating
hmm
but ah definitely you should go again I will I am
plugging of course that you a of course
go to the website.  You can complete and compare.
You can clearly see
who has more than 4.5.  Whose is less than 4.5?
Ok?  Yes definitely.  But this is a pretty
good score in claims experience.
Ok?
So the product with features has a rating of 4.5.
4.5 is the claim experience rating.  So
I believe that customer experience should also be good.
Not necessarily at all.  Yes.
Please share.   Let me
tell you about customer service.
Hitesh, basically in customer service, we as a
team
audit the
insurance companies on Twitter to see how quickly they
respond.  What is the average response time
of those people who are
filing any complaint, how does the insurance company
respond to anything.  Is Right Humanize Response
or not?  How much latency response occurs
or does not occur.  Well,
we have defined 10-12 such metrics and on that
basis we analyse their Twitter handles.
Correct?
Good.  So, their response time, if
we compare it
relatively to other insurance companies, is
average, meaning some are
not very exceptionally good, some are
not very bad either, theirs is average, is
n't it
similar to Twitter. We are analysing their toll
free services as well, how much
time it takes to connect with the agent on the toll free service
and all, so we do random mock calls
to the insurance companies, we
call them just to check what kind of
experience it is,
what qualities the people with whom we are talking at the call centre are
explaining the meaning of and all.  So
how quickly are you connecting
with the agent in this, right?
He is average in that too.  HDFC and Co
mean something extraordinary, not very good either.
Nothing too bad either.
Relatively speaking, he is average.
Meaning, it was not a very extraordinary
experience.
The third parameter in customer service is the
number of complaints received at the time of purchasing the policy.
Complaints will also come at the time of purchasing the policy.
This is also available in public disclosure.  This
data is also
very good for HDFC.  Which is 0.1%
and by the way this entire data of public
distr that I am talking about is for the
financial year 24 and the aggregate of the
three parameters in terms of customer service
HDFC Argo has been rated 3.5 out of
five that is why I told you not
necessarily right
3.5 relatively
got 3.5 out of five HDFC Argo
is okay in
getting it so we have rated HDFCO product
features as 4.5 claims experience as 4.5
but when it comes to customer
experience it is 3.5.  So based on all these three
things, I believe these three things
are the major three parameters on the basis of which
everything is covered and our entire
rating is made.
OK got it.  So you have already told me that the full
rating is made.  So give the final word,
how would you rate this particular one?  So
based on our methodology, HDFC Ergo's
Optima Secure plan has been rated 4.4
out of five considering all the three
parameters which are product benefits,
customer service and claims experience.
When we do the weighted average and relative scoring of these three across all the plans
out there.
Then it got a rating of 4.4 out of five.
And it is the highest rated plan on the
platform right now.
Oh yes
nice.
Got thank you Ayush.  For giving the entire
glimpse of how do we
see the product features then the customer
experience claims and taking all this we
read the product and customer experience
was 3.5 but still the product is rated
highest definitely the claims are very high.  The
product itself is very exactly
for sure.  So let's take a
persona and like you know discuss
how the premiums compare.  Meaning
not like this with like, let's compare it with like
three or four top insurance plans out there.
How does Secure's premium compare
?  Let me just check that out.  I have
already have it ready over here.  Like a
person of like let's say a 30 year old male
and a female
self and spouse
having a one year old kid.
Ok.
Ok?  and Living in Mumbai.
Ok?  What is there for this?  Meaning,
I am taking sum insured of Rs 10 lakh from Optima Secure because on
day one it has become Rs 20 lakh.
And I am comparing the other
insurance companies with cover amount of Rs 20 lakh.
Only That Makes Sense.  Right,
Optima Secure's 10 lakh policy is
₹28361, a bit
expensive. Right, ICICI LBD's Elevate
product is very recently launched.
We have
its ₹1 lakh sum insured
premium is ₹21999,
so there is a difference of around 56 kya,
yes, there is a difference of around 67 kya in this.
Right, nice,
so Elevate is the third product I am
taking Tata Medicare PME.
We have
Tata Medicare Premier's ₹20 lakh
policy is a bit expensive than Optima
Secure, it is ₹31230,
right,
and the fourth plan is Niva's
Aspire plan, Titanium Plus variant,
type selected,
its ₹1 lakh sum insured premium is
₹25493,
so it is a bit cheaper than like you know Optima
Secure. So, from an overall perspective, and
similarly, we have done the relative scoring
across all the plans.  There
and relative scoring in it, the
rate rating of premium
category is basically expensive for
Optima Secure.  Right?  And in this particular
test case also you can see
that Optima Secure is a slightly costlier
product as
compared to no other similar products there are.
So the thing which you discuss in the beginning is that buy one get one buy one buy one
premium is more of this brand.  Yes on the
other hand but yes the features are also good.
Hidden finishes are minimal.
Got it.  So thanks a lot Ayush.